<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="dlkerassimplernnlayer.png" type="Other">
	<name>Keras Simple RNN Layer</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Simple RNN layer.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Fully-connected RNN where the output is to be fed back to input.
			Corresponds to the
			<a href="https://keras.io/layers/recurrent/#simplernn">SimpleRNN Keras layer</a>
			.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Units">
				Dimensionality of the output space.
			</option>
			<option name="Activation">
				The activation function to use on the input transformations.
			</option>
			<option name="Use bias">
				If checked, a bias vector will be used.
			</option>
			<option name="Return sequences">
				Whether to return the last output in the output sequence or the full output sequence.
				If selected the output will have shape [time, units] otherwise the output
				will have shape [units].
			</option>
			<option name="Return state">
				Whether to return the hidden state in addition to the layer output.
				If selected the layer returns two tensors, the normal output and the hidden state of the layer.
				If sequences are returned, this also applies to the hidden state.
			</option>
			<option name="Dropout">
				Fraction of the units to drop for the linear transformation of the input.
			</option>
			<option name="Recurrent dropout">
				Fraction of the units to drop for the linear transformation of the recurrent state.
			</option>
			<option name="Go backwards">
				Whether to go backwards in time i.e. read the input sequence backwards.
			</option>
			<option name="Unroll">
				Whether to unroll the network i.e. convert it in a feed-forward network that reuses the layer's weights for each timestep.
				Unrolling can speed up an RNN but it's more memory-expensive and only suitable for short sequences.
				If the layer is not unrolled, a symbolic loop is used.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Initializers">
			<option name="Kernel initializer">
				Initializer for the weight matrix used for the linear transformations of the input.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/initializers/">initializers</a> for details on the available initializers.
			</option>
			<option name="Recurrent initializer">
				Initializer for the weight matrix used for the linear transformation of the recurrent connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/initializers/">initializers</a> for details on the available initializers.
			</option>
			<option name="Bias initializer">
				Initializer for the bias vector (if a bias is used).
				See <a href="https://keras.io/initializers/">initializers</a> for details on the available initializers.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Regularizers">
			<option name="Kernel regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the weight matrix.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
			<option name="Recurrent regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the weight matrix for the recurrent connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
			<option name="Bias regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the bias vector.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
			<option name="Activity regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the output of the layer i.e. its activation.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Constraints">
			<option name="Kernel constraint">
				Constraint on the weight matrix for the input connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/constraints/">constraints</a> for details on the available constraints.
			</option>
			<option name="Recurrent constraint">
				Constraint on the weight matrix for the recurrent connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/constraints/">constraints</a> for details on the available constraints.
			</option>
			<option name="Bias constraint">
				Constraint on the bias vector.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/constraints/">constraints</a> for details on the available constraints.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Deep Learning Network">
			The Keras deep learning network to which to add a
			<tt>Simple RNN</tt>
			layer.
		</inPort>
		<inPort name="Deep Learning" index="1">
			An optional Keras deep learning network that provides the initial state for this <tt>Simple RNN</tt> layer.
			The hidden state must have shape [units], where units must correspond to the number of units this layer uses.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Deep Learning Network">
			The Keras deep learning network with an added
			<tt>Simple RNN</tt>
			layer.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
