<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="dlkerascudnnlstmlayer.png" type="Other">
	<name>Keras CuDNN LSTM Layer</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Fast LSTM implementation backed by CuDNN.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Can only be run on GPU, with the TensorFlow backend. Corresponds to the
			<a href="https://keras.io/layers/recurrent/#cudnnlstm">CuDNNLSTM Keras layer</a>
			.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
		<option name="Name prefix">
			The name prefix of the layer. The prefix is complemented by an index suffix to obtain a unique layer name. If this option is unchecked, the name prefix is derived from the layer type.
		</option>
			<option name="Input tensor">
				The tensor to use as input for the layer.
			</option>
			<option name="First hidden state tensor">
				The tensor to use as initial state for the first hidden state in case the corresponding port is connected.
			</option>
			<option name="Second hidden state tensor">
				The tensor to use as initial state for the second hidden state in case the corresponding port is connected.
			</option>
			<option name="Units">
				Dimensionality of the output space.
			</option>
			<option name="Return sequences">
				Whether to return the last output in the output sequence or the full output sequence.
				If selected the output will have shape [time, units] otherwise the output
				will have shape [units].
			</option>
			<option name="Return state">
				Whether to return the hidden state in addition to the layer output.
				If selected the layer returns two tensors, the normal output and the hidden state of the layer.
				If sequences are returned, this also applies to the hidden state.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Initializers">
			<option name="Kernel initializer">
				Initializer for the weight matrix used for the linear transformations of the input.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/initializers/">initializers</a> for details on the available initializers.
			</option>
			<option name="Recurrent initializer">
				Initializer for the weight matrix used for the linear transformation of the recurrent connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/initializers/">initializers</a> for details on the available initializers.
			</option>
			<option name="Bias initializer">
				Initializer for the bias vector (if a bias is used).
				See <a href="https://keras.io/initializers/">initializers</a> for details on the available initializers.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Regularizers">
			<option name="Kernel regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the weight matrix.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
			<option name="Recurrent regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the weight matrix for the recurrent connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
			<option name="Bias regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the bias vector.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
			<option name="Activity regularizer">
				Regularizer function applied to the output of the layer i.e. its activation.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/regularizers/">regularizers</a> for details on the available regularizers.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Constraints">
			<option name="Kernel constraint">
				Constraint on the weight matrix for the input connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/constraints/">constraints</a> for details on the available constraints.
			</option>
			<option name="Recurrent constraint">
				Constraint on the weight matrix for the recurrent connection.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/constraints/">constraints</a> for details on the available constraints.
			</option>
			<option name="Bias constraint">
				Constraint on the bias vector.
				See <a href="https://keras.io/constraints/">constraints</a> for details on the available constraints.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Deep Learning Network">
			The Keras deep learning network to which to add an
			<tt>CuDNN LSTM</tt>
			layer.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Deep Learning Network">
			An optional Keras deep learning network providing the first initial state for this <tt>CuDNN LSTM</tt> layer.
			Note that if this port is connected, you also have to connect the second hidden state port.
			The hidden state must have shape [units], where units must correspond to the number of units this layer uses.
		</inPort>
		<inPort name="Deep Learning Network" index="2">
			An optional Keras deep learning network providing the second initial state for this <tt>CuDNN LSTM</tt> layer.
			Note that if this port is connected, you also have to connect the first hidden state port.
			The hidden state must have shape [units], where units must correspond to the number of units this layer uses.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Deep Learning Network">
			The Keras deep learning network with an added
			<tt>CuDNN LSTM</tt>
			layer.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
