<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="dlkerasembeddinglayer.png" type="Other" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
	<name>Keras Embedding Layer</name>

	<shortDescription>
		An embedding network layer.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			An embedding network layer.
			This layer receives a sequence of non-negative integer indices and learns to embed those into
			a high dimensional vector (the size of which is specified by output dimension).
			This layer can only be used as the first layer in a model (after the input layer).
			Corresponds to the
			<a href="https://keras.io/layers/embeddings/">Embedding Keras layer</a>.
			Note that the Keras documentation is outdated.
			The input to this layer can be of arbitrary rank and the output of this layer will have to be a tensor with one additional dimension.
			The inputs to this layer i.e. the values fed in the learner or executor must be integers in the interval [0, n) where n is the specified input dimension.
		</intro>
		<option name="Name prefix">
			The name prefix of the layer. The prefix is complemented by an index suffix to obtain a unique layer name. If this option is unchecked, the name prefix is derived from the layer type.
		</option>
		<option name="Input dimension">
			Size of vocabulary, i.e. maximum integer index + 1.
			The inputs to this layer during execution or learning must be integers in the interval [0, n) where n is the specified input dimension.
		</option>
		<option name="Output dimension">
			Dimension of the dense embedding.
		</option>
		<option name="Initializer">
			The initializer for the embedding matrix.
		</option>
		<option name="Embedding regularizer">
			An optional regularizer for the embedding matrix.
		</option>
		<option name="Constraint">
			An optional constraint for the embedding matrix.
		</option>
		<option name="Mask zero">
			Whether or not the input value 0 is a special "padding" value that should be masked out
			This is useful when using recurrent layers which may take variable length input.
			If this is selected then all subsequent layers in the model need to support masking or an exception will be raised during execution.
			If mask_zero is set to True, as a consequence, index 0 cannot be used in the vocabulary
			(input dimension should equal size of vocabulary + 1).
		</option>
		<option name="Input length">
			The optional length of the input sequences, when it is constant.
			This argument is required if you want to use dense layers after a flatten in subsequent parts of the network.
			Note that input length must refine the input shape, i.e. all dimensions must match if they are fixed.
		</option>
		<link href="https://www.knime.com/deeplearning/keras">
			KNIME Deep Learning Keras Integration
		</link>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Deep Learning Network">
			The Keras deep learning network to which to add an
			<tt>Embedding</tt>
			layer.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Deep Learning Network">
			The Keras deep learning network with an added
			<tt>Embedding</tt>
			layer.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
